wish.org 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy & Terms | Make-A-Wish® America

Make-A-Wish Foundation® of America (“Make-A-Wish”) respects the privacy interests and preferences of our donors and website visitors. We are committed to full transparency in outlining what information we collect about donors and visitors, how it is used and how you can opt-out of those programs (online or by traditional communications) if you so choose. 

### Personal contact information we collect and what we do with it 

When you are making a donation, purchasing a product, expressing an interest in referring a wish child, contributing to our guest book, or subscribing to our online newsletter, Make-A-Wish asks you for personal contact information such as your name, mailing address, phone number and e-mail address. We may use this contact information to provide you with a receipt or financial report; to contact you to clarify or obtain additional information about an order you placed, a donation you made, or a wish child you have referred; or to send you additional information about Make-A-Wish.

If you make a donation, we may contact you on occasion to offer you an opportunity to make another gift, or to inform you of promotions involving third-party sponsors that will directly benefit Make-A-Wish. You may also receive a personal call from a Make-A-Wish staff member or volunteer thanking you for your donation. You will always have the opportunity to opt-out of future communications from us.

From time to time, Make-A-Wish rents or exchanges its list of direct mail supporters with other trusted organizations to benefit our programs and activities. We have found this to be the most cost-effective method of reaching additional potential constituents and hope you value the information they send you. Your name is only made available to these carefully screened organizations through third-party mailing agents for a limited use. Such organizations will not have continued access to your name and address unless you choose to respond to their initial mailing. You have the opportunity to have your name removed from a list rental or exchange by writing to us at:

Make-A-Wish Foundation of America  
4742 N. 24th Street, Suite 400  
Phoenix, AZ  85016

Personal contact information may also be shared with certain vendors ( _i.e.,_ reputable companies we use for services such as shipping Make-A-Wish products or sending Make-A-Wish mail). We have confidentiality agreements in place with all such companies to protect your privacy. Finally, in some cases when you wish to refer a child, make a donation to your local chapter, or ask for local chapter information, your contact information may be passed on to your local chapter.

### Personal billing information we collect and what we do with it

In addition to personal contact information, we ask for billing information, such as your billing address and credit card number, when you make a donation or purchase a product. We use secure servers to gather and process your billing information. These secure servers are hosted by our agent, CharityWeb, which is bound by our site policies. Your billing information is not shared with any other organizations, and your credit card number is not retained once your transaction has been authorized and processed.

### Financial transactions and our secure servers

All financial transactions on our website, specifically donations and purchases, are managed through our agent, CharityWeb, which is TRUSTe certified. All transactions use an encrypted channel, take place on secure servers and occur in real time. No financial data, such as your credit card number, is transferred via a less-secure channel, such as encrypted e-mail, for processing. Moreover, once your transaction has been completed, your credit card number is not retained.

### Other contact information we collect and what we do with it

In some instances, we ask for contact information for people other than yourself including, for example, e-mail addresses of friends to whom you send e-cards or a copy of one of our Web pages, or the mailing address of someone you wish us to notify of a donation you have made. The information we collect is used to send the donation notification or information you requested and/or to inform the recipient of the opportunity to subscribe to receive Make-A-Wish updates, wish stories and opportunities to get involved. Such contact information is not shared with any other organizations nor is it added to any mailing list without the recipient’s explicit consent.

### How to view or change your information

If you do not wish to participate in our list rental or exchange activities, or if you wish to modify the frequency of future communications from Make-A-Wish, please write to us at our headquarters or e-mail address below.

Also, with the exception of credit card numbers, which are not retained, you can view and request changes to all the information you have given us, including any mailing lists you may be on, by contacting us.

Make-A-Wish Foundation of America   
Attention: Donor Care   
4742 N. 24th St., Suite 400  
Phoenix, AZ 85016-4862

E-mail address:  [donorcare@wish.org](mailto:donorcare@wish.org)

In addition, if you have subscribed to  _Wishnews_ ®(our online newsletter), you can unsubscribe by clicking on the unsubscribe link featured at the end of the newsletter. 

### Normal browsing

Make-A-Wish does not collect any personally identifying information from you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide such information to us.

You can browse the Make-A-Wish website without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself. The information we gather during normal browsing comes from two sources: (1) standard server logs collect information such as the IP (Internet Protocol) address, domain name, browser type, operating system and information like the site that referred you to us, the files you downloaded, the pages you visited and the dates/times of those visits; and (2) if you have come into the website from one of one of our newsletters or from a site that has requested a link, we will ask your browser to accept a “cookie” (defined below) that carries a general marketing source code with you as you browse through the website, in order to help us match referring sites to donations made. This cookie does not capture or hold any personally identifying information about you, and is deleted when you end your session by leaving our website or closing your browser.

### Cookies

When you visit our website, we might store some information on your computer in the form of a “cookie” (i.e., a small piece of data that stores information on your browser in your computer’s hard drive) or similar file. We use conversion tracking cookies as part of campaigns in order to analyze trends, gather broad demographic information and monitor website traffic patterns that can help us further develop and improve the design and functionality of our site. Similarly, we also use cookies for “retargeting” in our Internet advertising campaigns so that third party vendors, including Google, can show you advertising about Make-A-Wish as you browse the Internet. Retargeting is a marketing tool that identifies you as a previous visitor to the Make-A-Wish website and targets you for specific outreach messages, encouraging you to revisit our website or consider donating. Any personal information we gather will be kept private and not shared with other organizations. If you prefer, you can usually set your browser to refuse cookies, or to notify you when you receive a new cookie. You can also opt out of receiving cookies on the Make-A-Wish website for Google advertising by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page (http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/#toc-edit). 

### Links to other sites

This website contains links to other sites, including ones (such as eBay's auction site) that may gather personal contact information. Make-A-Wish is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such websites. However, any personal information obtained by us through other sites is treated as if it was gathered on our site and our privacy policy applies.

### Children

With respect to children, Make-A-Wish only collects personally identifiable contact information from children who are referring themselves as potential wish children. We pass that information on to the child's local Make-A-Wish chapter so the chapter can contact the child's family to make an assessment of wish eligibility; however, we do not share it in any other way or with any other parties. We do not give the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information in any way.

### Changes to this policy

Our Privacy Policy is subject to change from time to time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this Web page, and we will mark the link to our updated Privacy Policy on the home page of this website to note the date of any changes so that you will always know what information we collect, how we use it and what choices you have.
